A few months ago, I shared this video
teaching my earnings trading strategy
and it was a big hit. This video got
hundreds of comments from people who
tried the strategy and made profit. In
this video, I'm going to share not just
one but three strategies that you can
trade for earnings. I'm sharing this
example on Nvidia, but this strategy can
work on a lot of different stocks. This
video is for education purpose only. The
ideas shared in this video are not
recommendations. They are just examples
to demonstrate how the strategy works.
Earnings trades are highly risky. In a
losing trade, you can lose 50 to 100% of
your capital. So, consult your financial
advisor and do your own research before
making any decision. This strategy is
based on data, not luck or charting or
technical analysis. These strategies
have well over 75% win rate. For
example, for Nvidia over the last 3
years, if I traded this strategy on
Nvidia for every single earnings, the
first strategy would have had a 100% win
rate. The second strategy would also
have had a 100% win rate. And the third
strategy had 75% win rate. Most people
trade earnings based on gut feelings,
luck, or technical analysis. I don't use
any of that. My strategy is based on
purely on data and it does not require
watching charts. It is small account
friendly. You can trade this using as
little as a few hundred dollars and it
is very low effort. I only need 15
minutes to make these trades. Before we
go into the trade mechanics, understand
these two core concepts. The first is
expected move. An expected move
basically means how much the market is
anticipating a stock to go up or down by
given time period. In this case, the
market is expecting Nvidia to go up or
down by 5.7%.
We don't know whether it's going up. We
We know whether it's going down, but we
know that there's a high likelihood that
it is going to trade within this range.
And the second concept is implied
volatility. When implied volatility goes
up, option prices goes higher. When
implied volatility comes down, the
option prices also come down. Going into
the earnings, the IV is really juiced
up. So, it inflates the option prices.
And right after the earnings, the IV
comes down. In this case, historically,
the IV comes down by 12.4 8% for Nvidia
right after the earnings. And when that
happens, the option prices collapse,
which is why when you buy call or put
for options, you can lose even if you're
right. So, in this case, Nvidia is
trading around $190 at the time of this
video, but this can change by the
earnings date. And the expected move
right now is 5.7%,
which is a $10.8
up or down move. That means on the
downside, Nvidia can go till 179 or on
the upside, it can go till 200. So,
there is a very high chance that Nvidia
is going to open between 179 to $200
right after the earnings. Now, this is
not going to be completely accurate
every single time, but it is spot on
most of the times. Now, using this data,
we can trade three different strategies.
I went back and looked at Nvidia's
earnings performance for the last 3
years. And based on that data, I have
these clear patterns. The first is that
Nvidia opened green 11 out of 12 times.
That means right after earnings, either
Nvidia opened slightly higher or much
higher or at least flat. For most of the
times, there was only one scenario when
it opened in red, and even that was a
very small margin. And the second data
point is that Nvidia stayed within the
expected move nine out of 12 times. So,
that means 75% of the time it stays
within the given expected move. And it
did not break the downside move even a
single time over the last 12 earnings.
Now, using this data I can create three
different option strategies. The first
one is a short put strategy which has
had a 100% win rate over the last 3
years for Nvidia. That means that if we
sold a short put on Nvidia, we would
have won 100% of the times over the last
3 years. And even if we sold a put
credit spread, which we can do for a
significant smaller capital, that would
have also won 100% of the times over the
last 3 years. So, let's jump into
OptionShed and model some real trade
ideas. So, let's first sell a short put.
The expiration date is going to be 27th,
which is right after the earnings. And
since Nvidia is at 190 right now, we
know that the downside move is going to
be about 179. So, we can select
something just right under it. So, in
this case, if I select 177.5
put strike, it is going to be about 20
delta. And for this, I'm going to
receive $195 in credit, which is also
going to be my max profit. That means I
have about 84% chance of making profit
in the strategy. Now, let's model some
real trade ideas using these strategies.
The first one is going to have a higher
capital requirement, but I'm also going
to show you ideas with lower capital
requirement which you can do with as
little as a few hundred dollars. So, in
this case, first I'm going to select an
expiration date, which is going to be
February 27th. I want to select an
expiry which is right after the earnings
date. So, in this case, the earnings is
on the evening of 25th. So, I'm going to
select the 27th Feb expiration date.
Now, I want to sell a put which is
slightly under the expected move. We
know that Nvidia is trading at 190 and
the downside range is at 179. So, I'm
going to go out and sell a put which is
just below the downside range. So, this
is going to be at 177.5
strike, which is at 20 delta. That means
I have about 84% chance of profit in
this trade. I'm going to receive $195
credit. Now, if you're selling a
cash-secured put, the capital
requirement is going to be about $7,500.
Now, it says that this is also going to
be the max loss, but max loss is only
going to happen if NVDA goes to zero. I
don't think there is any possibility of
that happening. So, realistically, if
NVDA goes down 5 to 10%, we're going to
be okay because over here we have quite
a bit of downside protection. In this
case, we have 7.5% downside protection.
That means as long as NVDA stays over
177.5
after earnings, I get to keep this
credit as my profit. Now, in this case,
based on the data, I have a high degree
of confidence that NVDA is going to at
least stay flat or slightly higher after
earnings. So, I don't really need a lot
of downside protection, which is why I
can move my strike price to based on the
current price just under it so that I
have a little bit of downside
protection, but I am receiving more
credit. So, if I move my strike to
187.5,
which is just below the current price,
my credit is going to be much higher.
I'm going to receive $490 credit for
this, and now my break even is higher. I
have about 3.8% downside protection, and
69% chance of profit. Based on the data,
the data says that 11 out of 12 times
NVDA opened flat or higher. So, if that
trend holds, then I can make more profit
in this setup. Now, this one is at 42
delta. Anything under 50 delta is good.
If I'm selling a cash-secured put, then
the capital requirement is $18,260,
but I I also sell this put on margin and
in that case my margin requirement is
only going to be about $3,564
and I don't really have to pay any
interest on this margin. Now, if you
want to make this trade with just a few
hundred dollars and also significantly
reduce your risk, then I can buy a put
as a hedge and turn it into a put credit
spread. So, in that case, I can have
five to 10 point difference between both
strikes. So, if I'm selling 187.5
and buying 182.5, this is going to be a
five point put credit spread. Now, in
this case, my credit will be 175, but my
capital requirement is now only $325.
In this case, my max profit is capped at
175, my max loss is capped at 325.
That means I can make 54% return on my
investment in just a single overnight
trade.
And in this case, I also have a bit of
downside protection. I have about 2.1%
downside protection. That means if
Nvidia opens over 187.5
after earnings, I can capture most of
the profit right at market open. This is
where the concept of IV crush comes into
play. Now, in case after earnings on the
morning of 26th, if Nvidia opens at 190,
let's say it just stays flat and it
opens at 190. And in this case, you can
see that it can make 22% return on
investment, but in this case, the IV
crush is going to come into play. So,
let's simulate if IV comes down
significantly after earnings, you can
see that I can realize most of my
profit, which can be close to 35 to 40%
right at market open. Now, if you want
to increase your chances of profit, I
can reduce this strike to down to based
on the expected move. So, if I turn this
into a 175 and 180 put credit spread,
that means I'm selling 180 and buying
175 put. In this case, I will receive
about $99 credit and my max loss is
$401.
That means I can make 25% return on my
investment. And now the chance of profit
is 87% and the downside protection is
minus 5.7%. So in this case, even if
Nvidia drops down to $180, I can still
make 25% return. The IV crush is going
to help us here as well. So you can see
here that if I reduce the implied
volatility, it is going to capture most
of the profit right at market open on
the morning of 26th. If you would have
traded any of these strategies over the
last 3 years, every single time for
Nvidia earnings, you would have won
every single time. It had a 100% win
rate over the last 3 years, but that
does not means that it is going to win
every single time in the future as well.
It's possible that the next one it might
go down and things can be very
different. So for that reason, I like to
use another strategy called an iron
condor. In an iron condor, I can make
profit even if the stock goes up, even
if the stock goes down, or even if it
stays flat. So I have more possibilities
there, but because Nvidia has been a
very bullish stock for the last 3 years,
the win rate for the iron condor is
slightly lower than put spread, but it
is still very profitable. The win rate
has been 75% over the last 3 years. That
means nine wins and three losses. And
the losses that came to it were because
Nvidia went up a lot after earnings. So
let's go back to Option Strat and model
an iron condor trade. So again, I'm
going to select February 27th as the
expiration. The expiration date is
always the date immediately after the
earnings date. In an iron condor, I'm
going to sell both call and put and
capture premium with IV crush on both
sides. So in this case, we want to refer
back to our trading range. In this case,
we want to refer back to the expected
move, which is 179 on the downside and
200 on the upside. So, first I want to
move my short put strike to a point
which is right below the expected move,
and then I will move my call strike to a
point which is right above the expected
move. So, in this case, I can sell 177.5
put and 202.5 call, and I can turn this
into a five-point wide spread. So, I'm
going to buy a call at 207.5
and buy a put at 172.5.
Now, in this case, the profit and loss
graph looks like this. If Nvidia trades
between 177.5
to 202.5
after earnings, I can make maximum
profit. If it goes out of the range, in
that case, I can lose. So, for this
trade, I'm going to get $151 credit,
where my maximum loss is capped at $349,
and it has a 65% chance of profit, but
based on the historic data, this trade
has had a 75% win rate over the last 3
years.
And now, this has a protection on both
sides, but there is also risk on both
sides. So, after earnings, Nvidia has to
stay between 176 to 204 for this trade
to make some profit. The implied
volatility crush is also going to help
us in this trade. So, if we reduce the
implied volatility, you can see that it
can make well over 40% profit right at
market open if Nvidia opens within this
range. The main thing in this strategy
is the trade execution. Here is my
step-by-step workflow. The first thing I
do is look at the expected move, and
then find stocks which historically tend
to stay within the expected move, and
based on the historic data, I decide
what kind of strategy I want to go with.
Do I want to sell a put, a put spread,
an iron condor. There are some more
advanced strategies also that I use. And
then I open my trade right before market
close around 3:45 p.m. So, if the
earnings is reported in the evening,
then you will open the trade before
market close on the same day.
If the earnings are being reported in
the morning, then you will open the
trade a day before in the evening right
before the market close. And then the
most important part is taking profit.
I'm ready to take profit right at market
open next day.
The reason why you want to take profit
immediately after market open is because
there are going to be cases when the
trade opens in a big profit, but it can
quickly turns against to you because
after earnings, the stock can have a lot
of movement immediately after the market
open. For example, over the last 1 year,
I've seen this pattern with Nvidia that
Nvidia opens green most of the time, but
then people start to sell off. So, don't
forget to take profit. I need to open
the trade right before market close and
take profit right after the market open.
Don't have to watch chart. I'm just
relying on data. And this only takes
like 15 minutes of my day. I don't have
to watch my trades all day. I don't have
babysit it. I don't have to carry a lot
of large positions. I just make small
trades and make profits consistently
over time. Just like any trading
strategy, this strategy also have
certain risk, so it's very important to
understand them. The biggest risk is if
the stock gaps against you. So, in
Nvidia's case, Nvidia's biggest gap has
been about plus 26% over the last 3
years. Now, if you were selling a bull
put spread or if you were selling puts,
it would have made profit, but some
stocks can also gap down against you.
Past is not the future. All this data is
based on the past history.
The future can be different. The market
makers are very good and efficient at
pricing in the expected move. They have
access to a lot of data, algorithms, and
information and they're way smarter than
us. So, they can be right most of the
time, but sometimes even they can be
wrong. And in those cases, the trade is
going to lose. If you sell a cash
secured put in a worst case scenario,
you can take assignment of the stock. If
you're selling a naked put, either you
will have to cut the losses or you will
need to come up with the capital to
acquire the shares and ride it out for a
long time. So, using spreads can define
your risk and that way you can make
trade with just a few hundred dollars
where you do not have a big gap down
risk. And then the most important one is
position sizing. Do not risk large
amounts on a single trade. I like to
risk about 1 to 2% on a single trade, so
that if I win a trade, I'm up 1%. If I
lose a trade, I'm down 1% on my account.
I will not blow up my account because of
a single bad trade. And I tend to
diversify between different trades on
different tickers because I don't want
to put all my eggs in one basket. I'm
not going to make just one trade every
earning season. Ideally, I would like to
make a couple of trades every week. So,
that in a week, if I make four trades, I
win three out of them and lose one, I'm
going to be net profitable and I can
make consistent profits. Now, this
strategy works really, really well, but
what I've shared in this video is just
the tip of the iceberg. If you want to
learn and master the strategy in depth,
you can check out the details in the
description below in which I teach you
my step-by-step process on how I find
high win rate tickers. I share all my
scanners with you, how to select the
right option strategies.
I also have some even more advanced
strategies than what I've shared in this
video and how to set up the optimal
trade structure and how to be consistent
and get consistent results using the
strategy and how to use Use tools and
the data to find these setups within
minutes instead of spending all day
watching charts. If you have any
questions about the strategy, post them
in the comments and I will try to answer
as many as possible.